# **Damian Walsh**

damianwalsh.me
damianwalsh@me.com

# PRODUCT/INTERACTION DESIGNER BASED IN MANCHESTER, UK

### **SUMMARY**

I approach problem-solving methodically, developing useful solutions by understanding user needs and behaviours, as well as business objectives and technology. I believe in the value of craftsmanship that goes into creating best-in-class digital experiences and am happiest working as an individual contributor in roles where I can focus on delivering polished outputs that contribute to the success of the teams I work with.

### **SKILLS**

### User research

Understanding users goals and pain points using a range of methods including surveys, usability testing, competitor analysis and journey analytics to generate actionable insights.

### Interaction design

Collaborating with product, content, engineering and other stakeholders as part of an iterative design process, crafting experiences that resonate with users and deliver value.

# **Experimentation and testing**

Developing hypotheses based on observations and measuring the impact of experiments on success metrics through intent tests, A/B testing and conversion rate optimisation (CRO).

# **EXPERIENCE**

# JUL 2023 - PRESENT

### Freelance

Independent design consulting with a focus on visual design, interaction design, prototyping, and design systems. I can help design new products and features, develop brand assets and marketing content, or improve existing web and native app experiences.

# **MAY 2023 - JUL 2023**

# **Made Tech**

Public sector technology delivery experts.

# Senior Designer

As a senior-level individual contributor at the Met Office, I worked as part of an agile development team focused on developing consumer-facing native iOS and Android apps that adhere to Government Digital Service (GDS) standards. The team's main goal was improving weather forecast features, helping users make better decisions to stay safe and thrive.

# **Achievements**

 Championed design systems and helped the team transition from Sketch. Established the foundations of a themeable design system for native apps in Figma.

# MAR 2021 - MAY 2023

# Career break

Time spent focusing on personal goals, health and well-being.

# NOV 2015 - MAR 2021

# Booking.com

The world's leading provider of online travel and related services.

# **Lead Designer**

Responsible for design across the Peace of Mind product group. My role involved influencing, communicating and delivering design efforts aligned with the group's mission to provide customers and partners with clear and simple insurance alongside involvement in wider design team initiatives.

# **Achievements**

- Researched, designed and tested features including an improved product detail page offering customers clearer information.
- Contributed towards improving team culture through facilitation and participation in codesign activities and by securing sponsorship and coordinating events.
- Developed a tool to help teams identify ways of conducting user research and successfully made a case to extend licensing agreements of research tooling.
- Increased consistency and reuse of components across the customer journey and created documentation reducing compliance risk and time to onboard contributors.

### Senior Designer

Senior-level individual contributor across several Customer Service product teams. Designed new Help Centre and Live Chat features and improved transparency of information through the booking funnel achieving reductions in contact and cancellation.

### **DEC 2008 - NOV 2015**

#### Freelance

Independent freelance and contract design for various brands including BBC, Channel 4 and Tesco. Engagements ranged from developing prototypes and conducting user research to UI design and front-end development of responsive websites.

### DEC 2001 - DEC 2008

#### IG

A global leader in online trading and investments.

### **Head of Design**

Managed team responsible for UI and interaction design of award-winning online trading platforms. Established consistent visual design across a range of brands and products.

# Senior Designer

Assembled a cross-functional design team during a period of rapid company growth. Delivered localised marketing websites and campaign assets supporting international expansion.

# Web Designer

Part of the web team responsible for delivering financial and sports spread betting products during the period when the business began processing the majority of transactions online.

# AUG 2001 - DEC 2001

# **Tactical Marketing Group**

Integrated marketing services for well-known brands.

# **Contract Web Designer**

Designed marketing campaign websites and interactive games for clients including GlaxoSmithKline and Virgin Atlantic.

# JUN 2000 - AUG 2001

# Future plc

Specialist media publisher.

# **Online Editor**

Responsible for developing website features, creating/sourcing content and engaging with audiences through online channels.

# **NOV 1998 - JUN 2000**

# **Auto Trader Group plc**

UK and Ireland's largest digital automotive marketplace.

# Web Designer

Website and online marketing campaign design and production.

# VOLUNTEERING

# NOV 2015 - MAR 2021

# Northern User Experience (NUX)

# Organising committee member

A not-for-profit organisation run by volunteers which organises regular events across the North of England that attract high-profile speakers and up to 600 delegates in attendance.

# **EDUCATION**

# 1995 - 1998

# University of Plymouth

# BA (Hons) Media Arts, Communication and Media Studies

Developed critical thinking and practical skills across digital, moving images and photography.